OpenAI just took the best AI model in
the world, GPD5 High, and turned it into
a coding agent that can build
essentially anything. Yet somehow,
nobody is talking about this. It's
called Codex, and they just released a
hidden 2.0 update, which makes Codex the
best in class. Now, I've tried every AI
coding tool under the sun. Cloth code,
cursor, Devon, client, augment, you name
it, I've tried it. And after trying all
of these tools, I can confidently say
Codex is currently the best AI coding
agent in the world. And I would say it's
not even close. So in this video, I'll
show you the best way to use Codex, how
it compares to cloth code, and how you
can build anything with it. Now, it's no
secret that Enthropic's release of cloth
code has been an incredible success.
It's rumored that they reached 400
million ARR in just 6 months after
releasing Cloud Code. OpenAI has decided
that they want some of that juicy
revenue because developers have money
unlike a lot of different categories of
consumers. And so over the past few
weeks, they've been silently improving
Codex, shipping updates basically every
single day without doing any real
marketing, which is why Codex has become
so good without not many people knowing
how good it is. Now, Codex actually
isn't a single product. There's three
versions of Codex you have to
understand. The first version is the CH
GBD Codex that went viral earlier this
year. This is an AI agent that lives in
the cloud and can work asynchronously on
many different tasks. Then there's the
Codex CLI, aka OpenAI's own version of
cloth code. And this one has improved
massively. It used to be really bad, but
now it's actually very, very good. But
the best version of Codex, in my
opinion, is the Codex extension. This is
the real hidden gem that nobody knows
about, and it can be used from any IDE.
And I would say the release of the Codex
extension is a direct attack on cursor,
but we'll get to that later. Now, in
order to understand Codex, you have to
understand GPD5 high. GPD5 is not a
single model. It's a family of models
that comes in multiple different
versions, but the only useful one is
GPD5 high. The high stands for high
reasoning effort, and this means that
Codex can think for five plus minutes on
a single task. This is much longer than
Opus 4.1, and this is what's known as
test time compute. This ability to
reason for many minutes at once allows
Codex to go way deeper than CL code,
which makes it perform much better on
difficult programming tasks. And later
in the video, we'll compare these tools
side by side, so you can see the real
difference between Codex and Cloud Code.
Now, all of us want to use the best AI
tool possible, whether it is for coding
or for task management. So, here is what
Richard said earlier today in our
Discord server about Veal. I finally
realized what a kick-ass app this is.
Too many features that I like to
mention, so I'll just say incredible
work, David, and the team. If you don't
know what Veil is, it's an AI powered
task manager. So, for example, here I
said, "Today I want to focus on coding
and scaling my business, reorganize my
task list, and it updated 24 tasks,
saving me valuable time to focus on what
matters most." So, if you're serious
about AI and you want to maximize your
productivity, go to vector.ai and give
it a shot. You can get started
completely for free. Now, back to Codex.
So, let's look at the inside of the LLM
itself. For GPD5 High, 80% of the max
tokens are dedicated to the hidden
reasoning tokens, which means this model
is doing way more thinking than any
other LLM out there. On the other hand,
it has 22% fewer output tokens than 03
while achieving 50 to 80% better
performance. But here's the most
important part. The reasoning effort
parameter has four levels. Minimal, this
is no reasoning. This is basically
useless. It's worse than GPD4.1 somehow.
Then low, this is 0.2 ratio. Medium 0.5.
This is the default. And then high. This
is the magical one with 0.8 ratio. Now,
if you want to understand the future of
programming, you have to understand sync
versus async. When coding with AI, there
are two different paradigms of work.
Synchronous and asynchronous work.
Synchronous is when the AI agent works
alongside you on the same task. Async
aka asynchronous is when the AI agent
works separately, usually in a cloud, on
a different task or many different
tasks. But the beauty of Codex is that
it can do both. The CIGBD Codex agent is
asynchronous and the CLI and extension
are synchronous. So CEX itself can do
everything you need it to do when it
comes to AI programming. Now, actually,
there's a fourth Codex use case that you
must know about, and this just came like
two days ago. Codex can now also review
your pull requests, and you can think of
this as the cursor backbot, but on
steroids. Just in the last few days, for
me, Codex has been able to find serious
bugs that multiple human reviewers
missed. And this is especially important
because LLMs think differently than
humans. So, there are some bugs that
LLMs will completely miss that are
obvious to the human eye. But there are
also bugs that humans are completely
oblivious to that the LLMs can spot
easily. This is what makes the Codex
code reviews very very powerful. So
later in the video I'll show you how to
set this up because it's super easy and
it takes like 1 minute. So here is the
plan. I will show you how I use Codex
myself dayto-day to build my own AI
startup which is used by over 60,000
people. I'll also go over OpenAI's
official prompting guide for using GPD5
for coding. It was released last week
and it didn't get enough attention for
some reason. So we'll also look at that.
But if there's one thing that I can
promise you, it's that if you watch
until the end, you'll have the
confidence to build any software with AI
and specifically with Codex itself. So
now let's get to building. So I'm going
to build something that all of you can
start using today and that is a prompt
compression tool because it turns out
there's nothing good on the market,
right? So when you have a very long
prompt such as 70,000 tokens and you
want to make it 30 40% shorter without
losing any essential context, there's no
easy way to do that. So, I'm going to
load up cursor and we're going to use
codeex to build this project. So, let me
open a folder. Boom. Right here. Now,
you might think that GPT5 high, which
has 400,000 context window, would be
good at doing this one shot. However,
when I tried it and I told it explicitly
that I want a 30% shorter prompt, it
managed to turn 7,000 lines into 266,
which is not 30% shorter. That's 96%
shorter, which is terrible. So, we
cannot do that in one shot. We have to
first split the long prompt into chunks,
right? Then we have to rate each chunk
in terms of relevance and then run an
LLM a smaller one maybe like GBD4.1 on
each chunk separately and actually we
have to use code for constantly checking
the token count. So this is something
that LLM suck at you know you know the
famous strawberry how many hours there
are in strawberry. LMS are terrible at
this. So we're going to use codeex to
build this prompt compressor and at the
end of the video I'll give you the
GitHub repo so you can use this
yourself. To install Codex, you need to
run this command. npm-g
at open/codex. Copy this. Open the
global terminal. Boom. And paste this
inside. And that's it literally. Then
inside of cursor, go to extensions and
type in codex OpenAI coding agent. And
this one is the one we're looking for.
Make sure it's from official OpenAI. So
basically, it has the same powers as the
CLI, which by the way, you can then
launch with just pressing CEX. However,
it's sim it's nicer user interface,
right? You can see there's a chat box.
So you have switching of the effort
which you should instantly switch to
high. Same in the chat right when you
started just type in /model and switch
to GBD5 high. And we're going to be
using both to build our own project. So
before you do anything, no matter what
you're building, you want to create a
step-by-step plan. So I'm going to say
read build idea. This is what we are
going to be building. also read all
files in the previous attempts folder
because I already tried this with you
know existing tools such as LM lingua
from Microsoft which is terrible because
it uses small local LLMs to do the
compression and I don't trust no two
billion parameter model I want to be
using big models so I'm using voice to
prompt faster do not write any code yet
just analyze and prepare and output a
concise sixstep plan and there we go
we're going to start codex running and
this can take a few minutes. So in the
meantime, as I promised, let me go
through the six prompt engineering tips
from OpenAI on how to use GPD5 for
coding. Number one is be precise and
avoid conflicting information. The GPD5
family of models are significantly
better at instruction following, but
these models can struggle with vague or
conflicting instructions. So that's why
clear specific problems always yield
better results. The second tip is use
the right reasoning effort. You might be
thinking, okay, what does this mean
thinking and pro David? Well, this is
inside of JGBT, right? So, they have
auto, they have instant, they have
thinking mini, they have thinking inside
of here. To be honest, I only use
thinking. So, this tip, I honestly
disagree with OpenAI. I think you should
only use thinking and pro. You should
almost never use instant. And uh when
coding, you should just stick to high.
Do not use medium. Do not use low. They
produce much worse answers. Let's see
how Codex is doing. And we have the six
stage plan. So, say looks good. Now
append this plan at the bottom of the
build idea markdown file. All right. So
this is a good practice when doing
something. Do not just leave the context
hanging inside of the chat. Especially
if you're working on longer projects.
You have to document them in clear
markdown files. That way you can
reference them. Right? So maybe I switch
to cloud code which by the way this is
what my setup actually looks like.
Codeex on the left as the extension and
cloud code in the middle running 4.1.
It's much easier to do add build idea.
Boom. Than copy pasting and searching in
previous chats. you know, use markdown
files is what I'm trying to say. But
this is my text stack. And actually, the
next point is what my text stack looks
like. So, right now, I'm spending $420 a
month. Well, way more than that to be
honest. But at this very moment, it
costs $420 a month. So, first of all, we
have JGBD Pro, which is $200 a month for
maximum codeex access. Then we have
Cloth Max, $200 a month for maximum
cloth code access. And then we have
cursor. This is the only one on this
list that I'm not paying the full plan
for because I only use it for the cursor
tab really, right? So like when you're
writing documentation maybe we can go
here and can say it's more complicated.
Boom. It's suggesting you know it's more
like a process. So it's suggesting the
next word basically. So I use it for
that and I just use it for the role of
the ID obviously. Right. So you have the
terminals. Boom. You have the debugging
tools. You have the code editor which is
the main thing. You have the file
management source control. So this is
what I'm using cursor for right now. But
honestly this might change. The AI field
is evolving so rapidly. A month from
now, my AI stack may be completely
different. That's why you should
subscribe, by the way, because you need
to stay up to date with the latest and
greatest AI practices. So, go below
video and click subscribe. All right,
let's go back into cursor. Let's see if
Codex did this what I wanted. Yes, it
did. So, first of all, structure
chunking markdown aware chunker. All
right, so it split the plan into six
stages or six steps as I wanted. Looks
good. And now I'm going to have it
execute step by step. Good work. Now
create a new compressor.pi file and
execute step one. All right. And we're
going to set it off on step one. And
actually we can probably start using u
the CLI as well. I'll say read build
idea and spot any serious flaws or edge
cases. Now while that's going, let's go
into tip number three of the OpenAI
guide for GBD5 coding. And that is to
use XML tags. Right? So you will see
this in my file right here as well. I
use XML tags quite a lot to define the
sections. And this is huge because it
helps you structure your instructions
and help the AI agents actually follow
them. So, OpenAI recommends us to
delineate different sections of our
prompts to improve GPT5's understanding.
So, for example, you would have a
context section, I'm a software
developer, and then you have a task
explain object-oriented programming. And
the main benefit of this is reducing
misinterpretations because if you put
the XML tag at the start and end of each
section, the AI agent will know what
those instructions are about. All right,
let's see how Codex is doing. It is
still going. This is what I mean. High
is amazing. GPT5 high is thinking for so
long, way longer than Opus. Opus could
never. So this is really the first model
in the history of LLMs that utilizes
reinforcement learning the test time
compute the power of reasoning to the
fullest extent which is what makes it so
powerful. Now before we look at tips
four, five, and six from OpenAI, first
let me address a common thing I see of
people thinking that vectal is just a
to-do list app. If you think it's just a
to-do list, you're seriously missing
out. So this is what vectal looks like.
First we can create a task such as build
a prompt compressor tool in Python. Then
I can pin this task. Next up, I can use
the chat agent to help me work on this
task. So, let me select a different
model. Maybe we can use Gemini 2.5 Pro.
And I can say, what's the first thing I
need to do? Boom. And while it's
thinking, I can also go here and
generate steps. And with one click, I
can generate five steps on how to get
started on this. Right? So, the chat
agent fought for 6 seconds. Then, it
does perplexity web search, which by the
way, inside of vectal, we have
Perplexity Pro built in. All right. So,
the chat agent finished the web search.
It gave an answer. Then it updated the
task. And we can see that it added a
bunch of stuff into the task description
field. And then it gave me more ideas
about prompt compression techniques,
which actually we might implement some
of these in this video. So let me copy
this. I'm going to go back to cursor.
I'm going to go to build idea. I'm going
to add it right here. Research section.
Now this is just one of many things that
Vectel can do. For example, in your
notes, you can create what's called an
AI research. This is an automated daily
research about a specific topic. So in
my case it's about latest AI agent
problem techniques and as you can see
every single day vectal did automatic
research on this topic and out with it a
detailed report another OP thing that
you can do in vectal is you can have it
find the highest leverage task where's
the biggest task that will bring me
closest to my goals right now and by the
way if you're wondering how does it know
what your goals is this is exactly where
user context comes into play you fill
this out once and vectal knows
everything about you so if you want to
have AI agents helping you organize your
task list and complete your tasks go to
vectal.ai and sign up. You can get
started completely for free. All right,
now back to Codex. So, it implemented
step one, but it did it in a insanely
over complicated way. 300 lines is way
too much. Um, I'm going to say first
off, refine the sixstep plan to make it
simpler and less overgineered. Then I'm
going to reference the approach again.
Make sure to follow this approach. Next
up, in the meantime, I'm going to use
the correct CLI. So, first of all, it
identify these risks. Okay, let's see if
there's anything major. I think none of
these are actually that serious edge
cases. But what I'm going to do is I'm
going to tag the first file. I'm going
to say read build idea and then read
compressor. py. Your task is to heavily
simplify the Python file so that it
follows step one of the new simpler
stepbystep plan. The fewer lines of
code, the better. This is something I
should have said in the original prompt.
The fewer lines of code, the better. It
wouldn't have been 300 lines. So, that's
definitely my mistake. But let's look at
the reduced plan. How simpler it is.
Boom. Okay. So, we can actually view the
changes right here inside of the codex
extension. You can see a nice div of the
changes. And yeah, it looks a lot
simpler right now. So, another good
thing to do is to do a deep research
actually. So, I started this, but I'm
going to show you again. So inside of
you can use perplexity chb doesn't
matter gemini gro any tool that has deep
research which by the way we have that
in ve as well it's called ultras right
here and it's powered by perplexity deep
research but anyways I started the deep
research on this topic browse the web
and tell me the exact documentation for
openi API for using the gp4 model in
python so basically I want to make sure
we are following the latest and greatest
docs because codex just like cloud code
is a agent it's a agent And it uses a
model that is a training cutoff, also
known as a knowledge cutoff. Because
when you train a large language model,
you have to cut the train there at some
point and then do the training run after
which means it doesn't know what
happened yesterday, right? It can never
know that. That's why web browsing is so
essential and that's why doing a deep
research to get the latest documentation
and latest up-to-date info is so
essential and then giving context that
info will allow it to perform at the
highest possible levels. Let's see how
codex CLI is doing. So, as you can see,
it's basically the same as the
extension, but the extension is a much
simpler, cleaner user interface, right?
The CEX is more terminal based. It's
it's a CLI. It's a command line
interface. So, it's not going to be as
userfriendly, but it's just as powerful.
So, while that's going, let me explain,
as I promised, how to set up Codex for
pull request reviews because this is
very, very powerful and it's actually
very easy to set up. So, first go to
chbpt.com/codex.
This is the Async cloud-based agent,
right? So this is one of the free
versions of how to use Codex and the
other two we have right here. We have
the CLI, we have the extension, and then
this is the Codex agent in the cloud.
Right here there's this new button,
enable code review. When you click on
that, it moves you into the settings
where you can see your different
repositories. So on the left, make sure
you have code review selected and then
you can see your repos and you can
select on which repo the code review
should run automatically, which is
covered by my webcam, but you can see
these toggles right here, code review.
So you can just toggle codeex to run and
you'll need to enable it. There's going
to be like a button enable for GitHub.
You give it the necessary permissions
and then on any PR, let me switch to
GitHub here and open a pull request.
This is what I just finished
implementing earlier today. You will see
Codex automatically reviewing it. So
this is 12 hours ago when I created the
PR. All right. So I'm probably going to
have to blur some of this because this
is essential authentication for vectal.
You know, I'm actually doing what I
preach. I'm not just talking. I'm
actually walking the walk. I'm using
these tools to build my AI startup every
single day. So, I'm going to need to
blur that authentication. But what you
can do is you can do at Codex, are there
any major issues with this PR? What
should be the main things we test
manually in the app? And you can write
this comment and then CEX will react
with the ice emoji on this in a bit,
which means it acknowledged it and it
will start working on it. Oh, there we
go. So, there's this eye emoji. You can
see chbdc codex connector reacted with
the ice emoji and that means it's
looking at this PR. It has started
reasoning. get started analyzing the
files and it will give you a very
thorough PR review. Now, this is
especially OP if you combine it with
automated versel reviews, automated
cloth code reviews, the cursor backb and
you have all of these checking every
single PR which will spot a lot of bugs.
It will make your code more modular,
more scalable, and will just allow you
to ship way faster with a lot more
confidence. So, if you are working on a
bigger project, I highly recommend you
do this. It's very OP. All right, let's
switch the cursor. Let's see what
happened. So we had the Codex CLI
simplify this file from 300 how many?
330 which is crazy to just 86 which is
much much better. Okay. Next I will need
to add the GP4.1. So for this you
obviously need to go to platform.opAI
login with the same account you have as
for chat GPT takes like 30 seconds. Then
on the left click on API keys and create
new secret key. I created one named
subscribe. So if you're watching this
make sure to subscribe. and then create
an env file just env no other extension.
Now, do not share your API keys with
anybody, okay? I'll delete mine before
uploading this video. I'm just doing it
for educational purposes, obviously. But
in here, you need to type in OpenAI API
key and then equals and then paste in
the API key after that. Save that. Then,
in step two, we will use GB4.1 to rate
each chunks relevance. But for GB4.1 to
run, we obviously need to add the OpenAI
API in here. So, next up, let's let's
switch from between CLI and the
extension. I'm going to say this is much
better. Now execute step two. First read
the compressor. py file. Look how I
simplified it because your
implementation was way too long and way
too overengineered. And then execute
step two like a senior developer would
in the simplest way possible. The fewer
lines of code, the better. For the env
file, I created a new one in the root
folder. ENV. In there is the OpenAI API
key. So make sure to properly load that.
That way we can use GPT4.1 using the
OpenAI API. Next, I'm going to switch
and then I'm going to do actually
research. I'm actually going to docs.
This is going to be the XML section. So,
let's go back to the research here. I'm
going to copy the entire results and I'm
going to paste it here. I'm going to say
docs and just going to send it. Extra
context never hurts as long as it's
relevant. And now, GBD5 High is going to
implement step two using the results of
this DB search. So it will know how to
use GPD4.1. You know, it will know what
OpenAI API looks like right now and it
will implement a step regarding our
build idea. So right now we have the
chunking. So it can split the large
markdown into chunks. Let's look at it.
And it's nice that it will respect the
code fences, headings, li lists, and
stuff like that. So it won't just split
it into random chunks. It will be chunks
that make sense. While that's going,
let's look at tip number four from the
OpenAI prompting guide. And this is
avoid overly firm language. With other
models, you might use firm language like
B40. But with GPD5, it can backfire
because the model might overdo what it
would naturally do. So it can overthink,
overengineer, overanalyze. It can you do
way too many tool calls. If you use it,
whether it is the extension or the CLI,
you will sooner or later get a situation
where it does like 20, 30, 40 different
tool calls even on a simple task. So
this is the thing like sometimes being
overly strict, overly firm will backfire
because it will literally do like 15
tool calls for updating a single
documentation file where it already has
all the context, right? So being less
aggressive in your prompting can
actually be more effective with GBD5.
Now we can see codeex now was fast. So
sometimes it takes long, sometimes it
works fast. The allocation of the
reasoning effort is really intelligent
this way. And then it created a separate
file raider. And the function is to rate
the chunks with GB4.1. So let's look at
it. It loads the open API key from the
environment variable. And it gives each
chunk a rating 0 to 10 with float allow
so it can do decimal numbers. That's
nice. And then it asks, want a tiny demo
script to run? And actually I do. Yes, I
do want you to create this tiny demo
script. Keep it simple. So this is very
good. After you do each step, you should
test, right? So we didn't do any testing
after step one because it's just the
chunking. So then we did step two. So we
did two steps and now it's a good time
to just do a demo script. We should test
if these steps work correctly, if they
follow my vision before moving forward.
So two steps, step one, step two, and it
created a simple demo script. We can
look at it right here. Add a tiny demo
script to run checking rating on
original prompt. Okay, so we just
literally started and let's see if it
works. We have error. Max output tokens.
Let's see. So I'm going to copy this.
I'm going to say error again using XML
tags. Paste it inside. Close it. When I
ran that uh demo script, I got this
error. Explain what it is. Tell me what
is causing it and proposed a clean and
minimal fix. All right. So do not take
errors personally. Even when using
Codex, which right now is the most
advanced coding agent in the world, you
will run into errors. It's absolutely
expected. So yeah, just don't overthink
it. Don't take it personally. Don't let
it overwhelm you. Keep going. I guess in
the meantime we can go to tip number
five on how to use GBD5 for coding. Give
room for planning and self-reflection.
Let the model think first before taking
an action. This is what we did. Instead
of oneshotting it, which it might work,
it might not work. We split the task
into six separate steps. And I think
this is really the sweet spot. You know,
five to seven different categories. And
open they suggest to create a rubric
that has five to seven categories. So
before you do anything, doesn't matter
if you're adding a new feature or fixing
a bad bug, splitting it into smaller
steps is definitely the way to go. Also
use tags like self-reflection to improve
the reasoning of the model. So here you
have an example from OpenAI of how this
could look like. First spend time
thinking of a rubric until you are
confident. Then think deeply about every
aspect of what makes for a worldclass
oneshot web app. This rubric is critical
to get right. But do not show this to
the user. This is for your purposes
only. So basically you teach it how to
think. This allows the model to plan and
iterate the best possible approach
before it writes any code. All right,
let's see what happened. The API
responsor rejected max output tokens
eight. So I don't know why is it eight.
Make it 200. That's kind of funny
setting max output tokens so low. Yeah,
this is an error I've never had to
encounter before because um I never
wanted to output just eight tokens. But
since here we're doing the rating, I
guess uh that's that. Anyway, so let's
rerun this demo. Prints a concise JSON
summary with chunk counts and the 10
lowest scored. Okay, so right now we're
running u GB4.1. I guess I'm going to
say the issue with the demo or with the
current two Python files is that there
is no observability to the user. We are
not printing anything in the console. Uh
it's very hard to know what is
happening. So take a deep breath and add
four sensible print statements where it
makes sense. Right now I have no idea if
it's running or not, if there's uh any
progress happening and that's pretty bad
for debugging and building an app. Okay,
so it added two lines of code into
compressor.py and then two into Rator.
So now if we run the demo, we should be
able to see the progress logs. There we
go. Compressor splitting text 2,000.
Okay, almost 300,000 characters produced
117 chunks and then it's rating them.
Okay, so we need to run it in parallel,
right? So change the raider to actually
rate all of the chunks in parallel, not
sequentially. So we would be waiting
forever if this was sequential, right?
117 times calling GP4.1. Ain't nobody
got time for that. We need to run this
in parallel and u get the result way
faster. In the meantime, we can actually
get started on the first step. While the
extension codeex in extension is working
on this, we can start on the third step.
So, I'm going to say read build idea
again and execute step three like a
senior developer would. Make sure to
also read the compressor. py file and
the raider. py file. These are the files
for step one and two. You need to
understand them deeply and formally
before you execute step three. Take a
deep breath and implement step three in
as few lines of code as possible. The
simpler the better. All right. So now
I'm going to launch Codex CLI on this.
Let's see. We have um we have changes 32
+ 32 - 21 in Raider. So now if we launch
the demo, it should be running it in
async. Okay, wait. It's finished. So
never mind. That was way faster with the
async done rating. So there we go. File
original problem MD chunks 117 top
candidates. And there we have the ids of
the chunks that are the least relevant
basically. Wow. The problem is right now
we don't tell it to what right but okay
so I can actually ask that how is the
relevance being rated right now like
what is the relevance score being
compared against what does the prompt
for GPD4.1 look like I think there needs
to be some clear way such as in the
original prompt at the bottom
um it is relevant to this right these
claims so because this is structured in
a repo so that's how it looks
But we need to have we probably need to
ask the user relevant to what. All
right, let's see. Codex CLI implemented
a small step free module named
target.py. Okay, what I added target py
plan chunk returns using. So this is why
you need multiple agents by the way.
Whether it is a combination of codex
extension and cloud code or using codex
extension and codex cli. Sometimes you
need to ask questions to one while still
making progress with the other. So this
is why it's huge. All right. So this is
a big gap. Right now we don't ask the
author intent.
Okay. So this is definitely a flaw. This
should be the first step we do. It
should use the Python input to ask the
user in the console what is the intent
like what is the focus of this
compression. So yeah, we've spotted a
pretty serious flaw. How did we spot it?
just by testing it ourselves, writing a
small demo script and testing it and
seeing like okay it's rating the
relevance but what is it rating against
and that revealed a actually a gap in
our planning right let's look at the
target so step three is computing global
token target from desired reduction
problem is we also never ask this
another issue is that we never ask the
desired token reduction which is another
thing we should ask at the start of the
user now to be honest target probably
doesn't have to be a separate file uh
this could have easily been part of the
compressor I feel like maybe compressor
is a bad name here it's trying to make
it really modular which is good separate
files for separate functionalities but
um this is relatively simple project so
we don't have to make it ultra modular
now as I said earlier let's compare how
cloth code works compared to codex right
because you can see codex even for a
simple question just it doesn't format
it really nicely right cloud code is
much better at this opus 4.1 is
excellent at explaining concepts, at
teaching you things. So that's why my
stack is codex plus cloud code. But I'm
going to say start by reading the build
idea markdown file so that you
understand what we are working on. Then
find all of the Python files in our
codebase and read them in full and then
explain to me what exactly has been
implemented, what is missing and what's
the next step we should do. Think harder
answer in short. Demo is now going to
ask for the desired token intent. So
let's actually do this. Also update demo
to make use of target. This is our step
three implementation. Do not change
anything else. Boom.
Read the build ID again. Compress loop.
Okay, looks good. Actually, the CLI has
been performing quite nicely in terms of
being concise. So I'm going to say read
the build idea again. then read all of
the Python files again because I made
some updates and then take a deep breath
and execute step four of the build idea
like a senior developer would. The fewer
lines of code the better. And what's
also nice about the CLI is that you can
see the exact token counts. Right? So
here we can see 300 not 300 39,000
tokens used in this chat session and
that's 96% of the context window left.
So that's another nice thing that you do
not see in the extension and you do not
see it in close code either is uh
knowing how many how many tokens there
are in the conversation. That's why
having all of these tools, whether it is
the CLI, whether it's the extension or
the web- based chat GBT codecs, having
all of them at your arsenal really is
the way to go and trying all of them and
seeing what works, right? There's no
single dogma. Uh what works for me might
not work for you, but you you never know
unless you try. All right, so it seems
like our demo script has been improved.
Let's look at it. Let's run it again.
Step four is a separate file again. I
don't know why everything is a separate
file. Um maybe that's issue with me
being overly strict at the start. I said
modular now it's creating a separate
file for everything. So really when
OpenAI says this tip four
avoid overly firm language they do mean
it. You know Greg Brockman the
co-founder knows what he's talking about
right? So he's coding every single day.
He's using GBD5 more than anybody. So
listen to him. This these tips are
partially from him. And uh let's look at
it. So let's run the demo. It's it's
very interesting how each model reacts
differently, right? So offer intent
focus. So in this case, the original
prompt. So this is actually what we're
implementing in vectal by the way.
Desire reduction I want to do 40%.
Boom. So inside vector, we're adding
these workflows and it's basically
internal automations that allow you to
automate repetitive processes, right? So
let's say you want to have schedule like
every three hours have it brainstorm an
idea that's like a new marketing angle
or the default prom is a single
actionable idea that would get me closer
to my goals but it could be anything and
uh so right now I was investigating
whether we properly have limits or if
there's some bypass but it's already
fixed so don't worry so this is uh what
I needed this prompt but that's why it
has 7,000 lines and nearly 300,000
characters And let's look at the demo.
So this is not some like random prompt I
invented out of thin air. This is
something I actually needed for my
startup. So I'm building a solution to a
problem that I encountered. So okay, the
main difference is that the intent and
the focus, you know, it it asked us for
the intent and the focus and the
percentage reduction. Then it created a
token target. It would be nice to also
output the token length of the default.
So I'm going to say also it would be
nice to add a single print statement
that shows you the original full token
token count before the compression and
then show the token target after that.
So now we can see actually the chunks
that are properly rated
against the focus of this file right and
score the least relevant. So these are
the ones that we're going to be
compressing. We don't want to compress
the most relevant most important parts
of our problem. We're going to compress
the least relevant ones. Okay, so that's
good. Honestly, we probably cannot do
testing without step five and six. So,
I'm going to say now read step four
and tell me whether it fits well with
compressor raider
target. Take a deep breath and analyze
the original step-by-step implementation
plan inside of build idea.md
and then tell me if there are any
changes needed or if we can proceed to
step five. Do not make any changes yet.
Just analyze and answer. Be concise. All
right, let's look at the cloth code
prompt. So we can see you can already
see this like instantly you can see
cloth code is much cleaner. Do you see
this like nice heading, clean
formatting, you know, empty lines, the
outputs of um codeex are hard to read
like this is hard to read, you know, and
this uh also wording like if you wanted
to explain something, cloud code is much
better at explaining concepts at
teaching you stuff. Okay, I'll say read
step four. Is this a good execution
implementation? So it it clearly told me
what's implemented, what's missing and
yeah with cloud code you have much cloth
code is my favorite like consultant
right you have the codex as the coding
agent that's actually implementing the
code and creating the plan stuff like
that cloth code is like verifying
explaining checking providing second
opinion stuff like that this is the op
workflow right now it says proceed to
step five right in that case implement
step five like a senior developer would
only create a new file when necessary if
not put it into the compressor
py file. So we are definitely overdoing
it with files here. I'm going to say
does target really need to be a separate
file or should it
be inside of the main compressor py file
instead
think hard answer in short with clo code
this actually influences the reasoning
effort. So yeah before codex does any
action you can see how many tool calls
it does. It's kind of crazy right? Okay.
So now it updated compressor py since
only 20 line change and then
cloud core is suggesting we also merge
target. Okay. So I'm going to say also
do the same for target. py and I'm going
to do xml tags merge
merge.
Execute this simple refactor like a
senior developer would. I need you to
move the functionality from target. py
into the main compressor. py and then
delete the current target py file. Do
not do anything else. Do not add
complexity. The fewer lines of code, the
better. So being clear with your
prompting is really key. I'm going to
say
read all of the files again. Tell me
where we stand and tell me what needs to
be done next. Do not be lazy. Actually
open and read the files in full. Think
harder. Answer in short. So cloth code
has a much more consistent response
length. It doesn't have this big
variance where sometimes it responds in
10 seconds, sometimes it's 8 minutes.
Codex can easily take five, six, seven,
eight minutes to respond. Cloth code
doesn't. It can maybe take 2 minutes, 3
minutes at most, but you usually know
how long it will take, right? It will do
a couple of tool calls, some reasoning,
and it will respond. So it's much better
at chatting and like working fast. UI
changes. Close code is much better at
front end and UI because you can iterate
much faster. Codex tends to overthink
and overengineer. So uh okay, target was
deleted. That's good. What about step
four? Maybe step four is separate. Okay,
these look good. Step four is like 50
lines. That could be separate file.
Let's see implemented steps. Okay,
problems. Okay, so this actually pretty
good analysis. So I'm going to put this
as a plan. Boom. Again, using XML tags,
I'm going say, take a deep breath and
now execute this plan like a senior
developer would add enough comments to
make everything clear and well
explained. If you're a beginner, ask the
tools to add more comments, right? I
mean, comments should be used
everywhere, no matter what your skill
level is, but usually senior developers
can just read the code pretty well, but
the newer you are, the more more of a
beginner you are, the more comments you
need. So just ask for that like the
models can easily accompany your
request. So now basically we've
implemented everything step for sex step
six but there are some issues right step
four is missing the cis import. We don't
have a complete pipeline commanding all
steps and no final output which is the
step six stick chunks together in order
and write the result simple stats. Okay
so now we're going to create main.py
which is going to use these all the
files in a single place. I'm going to
say check whether your next steps were
executed correctly. Open and read main.
py and tell me if it's ready to be
tested on the original prom.md. And then
we'll say ultra thinking. This is the
highest level of reasoning effort for
cloud code. So listen code codex. I need
you to analyze all of the Python files
again and tell me whether we can test
the main original prompt MD file with
the new main. py. Is everything ready
for us to test all six steps or not?
Think harder. Answer in short. So, let's
allow this uh Python. I'm going to say
skip this. Focus on the code. Ultra
thing. So, it's it's trying to run some
Python commands to check imports, but
it's just a waste of time to be honest.
While that's running, let's look at the
last, but definitely not least important
tip from OpenAI's prompting guide for
GBD5 for coding. Control the eagerness
of your coding agent. GBD5 tries to be
thorough and comprehensive by default.
Use prompting to control how eager it
should be. Set boundaries on scope and
execution. So you can actually give it
like a tool budget. This is a very this
is a new concept that's very
interesting. Right? Instead of thinking
like a budget in terms of money or a
budget in terms of time, you give it a
tool budget. Like you can only call 10
tools and it can operate within that
budget. So it doesn't overthink, right?
So here is an example from OpenAI again.
So they wrapped it in the persistence
XML tasks. Do not ask the human to
confirm or clarify assumptions as you
can always adjust later. Decide what the
most reasonable assumption is. Proceed
with it and document it from the user's
reference after you finish acting.
That's very important. Documenting which
assumption it was acting upon. And this
is wrapped in the persistence XML tag.
So, it's encouraging the model to be
persistent and not to ask the user for,
you know, confirmations like a
lot of models do. Okay, it's saying step
four is missing some imports at the top.
So, what I'm going to do, I'm going to
copy the analysis and say analysis. This
is literally how I work by the way. I
asked another developer on my team to
analyze your execution and here's what
he said. What do you think of his
analysis? Is he overthinking? Is it
valid? Is it overly strict? or are there
any good and relevant points we need to
fix? And then I'm going to put the
response back. Boom. Here's the response
from the developer who coded these files
to your analysis.
What do you think of his response? Is it
valid or is he missing something? Think
harder. Answer in short. And then let's
go back up and let's look at the testing
instructions. Yes, it's ready to test
all six steps. So, let's do that. Let's
run main. py. Let's look at the offer
intent. Verify whether
rate limiting is proper.
Let's do u
25% reduction. So again, 288,000
characters at the start. Again, it
didn't tell me the token count at the
start, so I don't like that. Make sure
to update the relevant file to actually
tell me the token count at the start.
When you say compressor splitting text
and you say the total amount of
characters, I also want to see the total
amount of tokens at the start. Here's
what my terminal looks like when it's
running. As you can see, there is no
observability, no updates, nothing
telling me how many of the chunks have
been processed, how many of the agents
are running. I'm just waiting until all
have finished running, which is very bad
UI UX.
So your task is to find the best
possible spot where we should add one or
two print statements. So I have a bit
more info while the chunking is running
about how many of the 117
GBT4.1 agents have finished and how many
are still left and it should be rendered
like a simple loader bar. Boom. Let's
run that.
Let's open the terminal to see this is
still running by the way. How many?
Okay, I'm going to ask right now. How do
we decide the chunking? How many chunks
does it split into? Is that hardcoded?
Is that somehow calculated? How do we
decide how many tokens is in a chunk?
Analyze the code. Answer in short. So,
this is called dog fooding. You know,
testing your own tool, your own
software, and using it yourself, looking
where there's like lack of clarity when
something is missing. It's really
essential to build great software is to
be the number one user yourself. I mean
actually like inside of vectal I'm
always in the top five in the stats.
Obviously this is my testing account so
I'm like 300 but on my main account I'm
always in the top five and I'm using it
every single day for many hours and it's
saving me multiple hours per week. So
you know if you want to build great
software you have to be one of the most
power users, one of the highest users of
that software to spot the bugs and to
really feel what's wrong with it. Okay.
Split by mark. Okay. One chunk refriger
blocks.
This is kind of bad, by the way. I don't
like this at all. Instead, we should be
chunking it into roughly 4,000 token
amounts. Obviously, we should respect
the boundaries of the markdown rule, but
we should make sure that each chunk is
between four and 8,000 tokens. So we can
see there's multiple flaws. You cannot
just let these models to their own
devices. You have to be involved, right?
You have to be leading the product. You
have to be leading the feature
directions so that you actually can see
what's happening because the models are
bad at making decisions. They're really
good at writing code and at spotting
bugs. They're bad at deciding, you know,
what what's the feature, what the
product should look like, how should it
feel. All of that is your
responsibility. So people who say like
AI is going to replace programmers,
they're clueless. They're not using it
day-to-day. I use it every single day
and I have a team of developers using it
every single day. And trust me, the
models are not going to replace
programmers. They're going to make them
smarter and for the next 5 years, the
future is going to be human plus agent.
Human plus agent will destroy AI only.
Okay, this is a quite a bigger change.
113 new lines and five removals. Still,
compressor is quite manageable. 230
lines is fine. And by the way, if you're
liking what you're seeing, all of this
content is exactly what we have in the
new society. So if you want to go
deeper, if you're serious about AI
coding and you want to become a 10x AI
developer, an AI first developer, then
inside of the classroom, we have
multiple workshops just on this topic.
So if I scroll down right here, we have
an entire section on code with AI that
has multiple different workshops on
cloth code, on cursor codeex. So this is
the codex, this is when it originally
came out. six modules on that, three
modules on cloth code, two modules on
cursor, and this is just one of many
different courses we have inside of the
classroom of New Society. So, if you're
serious about AI, if you want to take it
to the next level, and perhaps if you
want to start making money with AI, join
the New Society. It's going to be linked
below the video. All right, so the
compressor changes have been made. Let's
run it again. I really want to see how
well it makes and I I want to finish
this because I'll be using it myself,
this prompt compressor. I'm not building
some like throwaway, you know, vibe
coded stuff. I'm building something I
will need to use day-to-day. Check if
user limits are correctly applied. We
want to do let's do a 45% reduction.
Okay.
Okay. Original target. All right. So,
spring text.
So, this is using different tokenizer
than repo because in repo prom this was
like 30 74,000 tokens. Here it
calculates at 60,000. Then it produced
nine chunks.
H. We might need to change the chunking
logic.
Change the chunking thresholds to be
between 2,000 and 4,000 tokens each.
Change it to be between 2 and 4,000. Not
4 to 8,000 like it is now. Do not change
anything else. So again, we have no
nothing happening when this is running.
So I'm going to say still when the
script is running nothing is happening
at this stage I'm going to say terminal
boom paste it in
close the terminal XML tags identify
what point of the main py script this is
and implement more logging more print
statements so I can actually see what is
happening. So, we updated it to be two
to 4,000. That's much better. Before it
was like way too many chunks, you know,
like 117 chunks. Like that's too many
API calls. But then, uh, it was only
like nine chunks when we did 4 to 8,000.
So, I think 2 to 4,000 will be better.
In the meantime, what we can do is we
can set up the GitHub stuff. So, I can
go to my GitHub repos,
new repo. I'm going to say prompt
compressor. I'm going to make it public.
This tool can compress any prompt by a
given percentage amount. Ideal for very
long prompts. Okay. Uh license. Let's do
MIT, which is full open source. Git
ignore. We can probably add it. So,
actually, we should probably add a git
ignore. Analyze all the dependencies,
all the environment files we have,
everything. And add a proper git ignore
into the root folder covering
everything. Okay. So, we're going to
leave that empty. Create repository.
Then I'm going to copy this link of the
repo and I'm going to help cloud code.
I'm going to have cloud code uh correct
this. Well, actually, let's use codex.
So, boom. I'm going to actually do slash
new to start a new chat session. I'm
going to do use I'm going to break my
rule because I want fast responses. I'm
going to use GBD5 low. I say your task
is to help me connect my local project
to this GitHub repo. Tell me what to do
step by step. Okay, so let's see. Cloud
code has created the git ignore. So even
on the low reasoning effort, it still
takes a bunch of time to respond. So
actually I'm going to use cloud code for
this because again cloud code is better
at quick changes. It's not as powerful
as Codex. It's easier to use for sure.
So the best use case as I said multiple
times is codeex plus cloud code and to
be honest if you are starting out you
just need the 20 $20 a month plan on
both of these right anyways let's
initialize the repo following the steps
if you've never done it I mean obviously
I have tons of repos but if you've never
used GitHub just ask the AI agents have
them help you it's the most underrated
thing like a lot of people make excuses
where it's literally like one or two
prompts like most of your excuses are
literally one or two prompts to an LLM.
Think about that. All right, so let's
send this. Boom. What's the issue here?
Is it misformatted or something? Get
remote add origin paste. Okay, there we
go. Get add dot to stage all the files.
So we can go to the
source control here. We can see all all
those things have been staged.
And then
we just do original commit and push it
with upstream. Get commit first commit.
Actually, this this commit message is
pretty good. You can just steal this.
Boom. And then we need to set the main
branch as being the master. Get branch.m
M-m main. And then we need to push it
with upstream tracking. That way we can
then just do get push and it knows which
branch is connected. Get push upstream
origin main. And what's what's the
issue?
Oh, we need to fetch first. Get pull.
Oh, because we have the license. What is
the issue?
Get pull.
There's no tracking for the current
branch. So, I have this error. I'm going
to have LLM help me resolve it. Is Codex
finally finished? Okay, there it is.
Error. Boom. Okay, so I implemented all
the steps but when I tried pushing with
upstream, I got an error saying that I
need to pull first. So when I do get
pull,
okay, I know what the issue is. I just
realized what the issue is. We don't
have the upstream tracking. So we need
to do get pull origin main. Okay, we
need we need some parameters. You know
what? Let's do force push. Tell me how
to do the upstream push but with force.
We have some changes that we need to
overwrite. There we go. We need this
command. Boom.
And then if we go here, we reload, we
have everything, but we lost the
license. So I can just ask codeex. Next
up, analyze our entire repository, read
all of the files, and create a license
file that is a complete MIT license.
Everything open source, everything
allowed. Okay, that's good. So now we
have it on GitHub. And I'm going to link
this below the video so you can just
take it, you know. Hopefully there is no
ENV file. There is not. That's good.
We have some previous attempts. Uh,
original prompt. I should probably
remove that. Or actually, I don't know.
It's probably fine. I mean, you guys can
use your own prompt, so all right. So, I
had to do a few fixes off camera, but
it's ready. So, I added the license
file. I added the readme file. Stuff
that every GitHub repo should have. And
again, it's completely open source, so
you can feel free to use it. I'm going
to link it below the video. Um, if you
have long prompts, this is the way to go
to compress them. Hopefully you found
this video useful. This is my this is
how I use it. I use cloth code for you
know quick actions for explaining what
to do for teaching me concepts and I use
codeex for the heavyduty programming for
the most complex error fixing feature
implementation anywhere I need the most
all the power I can get. GPD5 high is
right now the best AI model for
programming. Opus 4.1 also really good
but it's not as powerful. It doesn't
reason as much. That's why it's better
for being like more of the assistant,
more of the consultant, right? Whereas
the actual AI coding agent is Codex with
GBD5 Highi. So this is my tech stack as
of early September of 2025. AI field is
improving so fast. So who knows, might
literally change in the next month, in
the next two weeks. We'll see. But yeah,
hopefully you found this video useful.
If you did, and if you're interested in
more content like this, make sure to
join the new society in the classroom.
You're going to upskill yourself from a
complete beginner to someone who's
better than 99% of people at AI. If you
want to become an AI first developer,
which means a developer who will not get
replaced, instead who companies will try
to keep and promote, this is the place
to be at. No matter what your experience
is, no matter if you've never coded
before or if you have coded but you're
not using AI, if you join a new new
society and if you go through the
content we have in the classroom, you
will become better than 99.9% of people
with AI. And that is a promise because
I've spent well over thousand hours
using AI tools for coding and I've
documented everything in here. And
actually I've even documented my startup
literally from day one documented the
rise of vectal from the idea to choosing
to building the back end error hell the
path my plan to 10 mil deploying it
choosing the do name the domain name
blah blah blah everything is in here. So
yeah, if you want to build your own SAS,
literally I showed you how I did it from
zero to over $10,000 MR. So if you're
serious about AI, join new society. It's
going to be linked below. With that
being said, thank you guys for watching
and I wish you a wonderful, productive
week. See you.